コードギアス反逆のルルーシュR2 TURN 23　シュナイゼル　の　仮面
TURN 23　シュナイゼル　の　仮面
神聖ブリタニア帝国?本土
フレイヤ弾頭による巨大な穴が
ルルーシィたちの人質になった各国代表
天子をだきしめる神楽耶
兵士たちの噂話
といって倒れる咲世子
ナナリーと会話するルルーシュたち
とシュナイゼル
うっ
銃弾が放たれ 撃たれるコーネリア
そばにつきそうジェレミアに事情を話します
ベッドにこしかけるルルーシュ
ルルーシュの手に自分の手をかさねるC.C.
コンピューターにむかうニーナとロイドさん セシル
前にでてきた鎮魂のローソク
決意をかためて歩くルルーシュ
戦争の準備は着々と
中華連邦で演説するシンクーはあいかわらず血をはいているようで
日本では 人々を前に玉城がはりきっています
水無瀬たち
藤堂さんを見て顔をあからめる千葉
おなかをおさえるヴィレッタと扇
ラクシャータ
カレンとジノ
神楽耶と天子がうつります
扇に伝えるシンクー
アヴァロンに衝撃がつたわり
天子をだきしめる神楽耶の目に涙がうかんでいます
お腹に赤ちゃん
回想おわり
Holy Britannian Empire - Homeland
て 帝都ペンドラゴンが消滅した？
The... The capital Pendragon's been annihilated?!
本当か？それは
Is it really true?!
フレイヤ弾頭らしい
Looks like it was
a F.L.E.I.J.A. warhead.
トウキョウ租界を壊滅させた？
The thing that wiped out
the Tokyo settlement?
事故か？
Was it an accident?
しかし 製造したはずのフレイヤはなくなっていると
But I've heard all the F.L.E.I.J.A. s
they manufactured are gone.
軽挙妄動は慎め
Stop spreading wild stories!
帝都が消滅だと？
Even if it's just rumors, it's imprudent
to discuss the capital's destruction!
噂話だとしても不謹慎である
いいえ おそらく本当のことです
No, I'm afraid it's true.
何っ？あっ　君は
What?! You!
ルルーシュ様にお取次ぎ　を
Please...
Take me to Master Lelouch!
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
Kireigoto dake jaa ikirenai
Pretty words alone won't sustain you
Yasashisa dake jaa iyasenai
Kindness alone won't heal you
Ubawareta nowa nanda
What is it that was stolen from you
Kawaranai sekai de
In this unchanging world
Kikoetekita nowa nanda
What is it that you hear
Shikisai no uta
A song of color
Everything is bright...
Kudakechitta yume wo
Let our crumbled dreams resound
Asu no hate ni hibikaseru you ni
At the edge of tomorrow
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Bokura hitotsu ni
Becomes one with us
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
SCHNEIZEL'S GUISE
ナ　ナナリー生きて　いたのか
N-Nunnally... You're still alive!
はいシュナイゼル兄様のおかげで
Yes, thanks to Brother Schneizel.
シュナイゼル？
Schneizel...
ナナリー 君はシュナイゼルが何をしたのかわかっているのかい？
Nunnally... Do you understand
what Schneizel has done?
はい帝都ペンドラゴンにフレイヤ弾頭を撃ち込んだ
Yes. He's attacked the capital,
Pendragon, with a F.L.E.I.J.A. warhead.
それがわかっていてなぜ！？
If you know that,
then why?!
では　ギアスの方が正しいというのですか？
Are you saying using
Geass is better?!
お兄様もスザクさんも
You and big brother have been
lying to me all along, haven't you?
ずっと私に嘘をついていたのですね
本当のことをずっと黙って
You've kept the truth
from me all this time.
でも 私は知りました
But I found out.
お兄様がゼロだったのですね
Big brother, you were Zero
all along, weren't you?
はっ
どうして
Why?! Were you doing it for my sake?
If that's the case, then l...
それは　私のためですか？
もしそうなら 私は
ふはははっお前のため？
For your sake? I see my little
sister is as presumptuous as ever!
我が妹ながら図々しいことだ
はっ
人からお恵みを頂くことが当たり前だと考えているのか？
Do you think it's natural for people
to always help you out of pity?
自らは手を汚さず　他人の行動だけを責める
All you do is criticize the actions of others
while your own hands remain undirtied.
あっ
お前は俺が否定した古い貴族そのものだな
You are the very embodiment of
the aristocracy which I have rejected.
そん　な
You... don't...
誰のためでもない
I do this for no one! It is for my
own benefit that I take the world!
俺は　俺自身のために世界を手に入れる
お前がシュナイゼルと手を組み
If you choose to ally yourself
with Schneizel and stand in my way,
我が覇道の前に立ちはだかるというのなら容赦はしない
I have no choice but
to crush you without mercy!
叩き潰すだけだ
おにいさま
通信をきるルルーシュ
Big brother!
大丈夫か？ナナリー
Are you all right, Nunnally?
つらい思いをさせてしまったね
That must have
been hard for you.
フレイヤの威力をみせれば　降伏してくれるとおもったんだけど
I thought showing him the power of the
F.L.E.I.J.A. would lead him to surrender.
シュナイゼル兄様
Schneizel... Are the people
of Pendragon really all right?
ペンドラゴンの人たちは本当に大丈夫なのですか？
心配いらないよあらかじめ　避難誘導をすませたからね
You needn't worry. We gave warning
for them to evacuate beforehand.
もちろん 被害が皆無とはいかないけれど
Of course, the damage was significant,
but we tried to minimize it.
最小限にとどめたつもりだよ
でも　次は人に　お兄様たちにつかうのでしょう？
シュナイゼルの言葉をきいてうつむくコーネリア
But, now... Now we'll have to use
them on people. On big brother, right?
彼らが　世界平和の前に立ちはだかるのならば
If they stand in the way
of world peace, we will.
シュナイゼル兄様
Brother Schneizel...
私に フレイヤの発射スイッチをいただけませんか？
Will you let me have the
F.L.E.I.J.A. firing switch, please?
私は戦うことも　守ることもできません
I can't fight or protect
anything myself.
だから　せめて　罪だけは背負いたいんです
That's why, at the very least...
I want this sin to be on my shoulders.
兄上少しよろしいですか
Brother, may I have
a word with you?
くっ
C.C.！なぜナナリーのことがわからなかった？！
C.C., why didn't you
know about Nunnally?!
私は神ではない
I'm not a god. I can't know about
anyone unconnected to Geass.
ギアスによるつながりがない人間のことまでは
くっシュナイゼルめ
Damn you, Schneizel!
You kept the truth from me all this time!
この事実を今までかくしておいたのか
カードとして効果的につかうために
Just so you could play this card
when the time was right!
チェスの駒をはらいおとすルルーシュ
ならば 貴様のカードの切り方は絶妙だったぞ
Still, the way you shuffled
your deck was extraordinary!
こんなにも　こんなにも　ううっ
So masterfully...
So masterfully!!!
ルルーシュ
胸をおさえるルルーシュ
Lelouch.
ルルーシュに近づき胸倉をつかみあげるスザク
戦略目的は変わらない
Our strategic objective
remains unchanged.
ナナリーが生きていたからといって
We can't stop this just
because Nunnally is still alive!
立ち止まることはできない
何のためのゼロレクイエムだ？！
What's the point of
the Zero Requiem, then?!
ルルーシュを突き放します
約束を思い出せ
Remember your promise!
部屋からでていくスザクをよびとめるC.C.
スザク
Suzaku!
僕は彼の剣だ彼の敵も弱さも僕が排除する
I am his sword. I rid him of his
enemies and his own weakness.
だからC.C. 君は盾になってくれ
So, C.C., you must
become his shield!
守るのは君の役目だ
Protecting him is your duty.
勝手な言い分だな
That's only what you think.
ルルーシュは 君の共犯者なんだろう？
Lelouch is your accomplice, isn't he?
共犯者　か
My accomplice, huh?
セシルさんとロイドさんとニーナ
ペンドラゴンでつかわれたフレイヤは
Compared to the F.L.E.I.J.A.
used on the Tokyo settlement,
トウキョウ租界のときにくらべて
the one used on Pendragon
had ten times the effective range.
効果範囲はおよそ10倍
新規生産ではないとすると
If they haven't manufactured
a new model, then...
リミッターを　はずした　？
They've removed
the limiter from it.
やっぱり
I'm sure of it.
効果範囲と起爆時間の制限をはずすなんて
Removing the effective range
and detonation time limiter...
シュナイゼル殿下が
Prince Schneizel, how could you?
それがなにか？
What about it?
で では ペンドラゴンの住民は　？
You mean the people
of Pendragon were!
消えてもらったよ
I made them vanish.
その方が幸せじゃないのかな
Happier for them than a life
swearing loyalty to Lelouch, isn't it?
ルルーシュに忠誠を誓う人生よりは
しかし ナナリーには
But, you told Nunnally...
嘘も方便だよ
Lies are expedient.
ナナリーがルルーシュに立ち向かうと決意してもらうには
No need to tell Nunnally anything...
that would get in the way of
her opposition to Lelouch, is there?
よけいな情報は　いれないほうがいいだろう？
兄上はそうやって人をあやつるのですか？
Is that how you use
people, Brother?
コーネリア　人々の願いはなんだい？
Cornelia, what is it
that people wish for?
飢餓や貧困
Starvation and poverty.
差別 腐敗
Discrimination and corruption.
戦争とテロリズム
War and terrorism.
世界にあふれる問題をなくしたいと願いつつ
They wish for the problems
flooding the world to go away.
人は絶望的なまでにわかりあえない
People desperately cannot
understand each other. And so...
なら
理想としてはわかりますが 民間人を
I understand your ideals,
but to do this to the civilians!
う～ん
Yes...
戦争を否定する民間人だって警察は頼りにするよね？
Even civilians who have rejected war
depend on the police, don't they?
みんなわかっているんだ
Everyone understands
that crime cannot be stopped...
犯罪はとめられないと
人それぞれの欲望は 否定できないと
because people can't
help the desires they have.
だったら 心や主義主張はいらない
That's why we don't need
to win hearts or use ideology.
システムと力で 平和を実現すべきでは？
Why not bring peace to
the world using a system backed by force?
このダモクレスは　10日後に合集国中華の領空にはいり
In 10 days, Damocles will enter the
airspace of the United States of China...
第二次加速に移行する
and then switch over
to secondary acceleration.
その後 地上300キロメートルまで上昇する予定だ
After that, we're scheduled to ascend
to 300 kilometers above the surface.
その位置から 戦争を行うすべての国にフレイヤを撃ちこむ
From that position, we will hit every
warmongering nation with F.L.E.I.J.A.s.
待って下さい！
Wait! Shouldn't they be used to defeat
Lelouch?! This will devastate the world!
ルルーシュを討つためだったのではなかったのですか？
これでは世界中が
恐怖で人を従えようというのですか？
You're going to control
people through fear?!
平和というのは幻想だよ
Peace is an illusion.
戦うことが人の歴史
Mankind's history is one of war.
幻想を現実にするためには　しつけが必要では？
Is not discipline what is needed
to make an illusion reality?
人類を教育するつもりですか！？
And you plan to teach that lesson
to the entire human race?!
そのようなことは　神でなければ許されない！
Only God can get away
with something like that!
だったら 神になろう
Then I shall become a God.
人々が　平和を私に望むのならば
If that is what people want me
to become to give them peace.
あなたは
You...
素晴らしい！
Magnificent!
やっぱりあなたについてきて正解でした！
I knew I was right
to come with you!
ゼロのカオスをも凌駕する完璧な虚無
Surpassing Zero's chaos to
a state of perfect nothingness,
多様なる変幻
followed by a kaleidoscopic
transformation!
シュナイゼル殿下黒の騎士団と連絡がつきました
Prince Schneizel, we've made
contact with the Black Knights.
ルルーシュを討つためならば　手を組むと
They say if you plan to kill Lelouch,
they're willing to help.
ありがとう
Thank you.
ルルーシュの暴虐を経験した民衆は
The masses who suffer Lelouch's
tyranny will have no choice...
よりましなアイデアにすがるしかないよね
but to cling to something
slightly better.
そのために
Are you saying that's why you've let
Lelouch get away with this until now?!
ルルーシュの行動をみすごしたというのですか？
もっとも被害の少ない方法だよ
It was the way to
minimize the damage.
たとえ10億　20億の命がなくなったとしても
Even if we lose 1 or 2 billion lives,
for a permanent peace...
恒久的な平和が
違います！
You're wrong!
Peace given by force is no peace!
強制的な平和など それは
シュナイゼルが指で合図すると
悲しいねコーネリア
You make me sad, Cornelia.
手当をうけた咲世子さんは
トウキョウ決戦のとき
Schneizel had another escape plane as a
decoy during the battle for Tokyo. And so...
シュナイゼルは囮として　もう一機　脱出艇を
だから
フレイヤで消失したのは囮のほうか
Then the plane destroyed by
the F.L.E.I.J.A. was the decoy.
ナナリー様を利用して
He's trying to use Miss Nunnally
to control Master Lelouch!
ルルーシュ様をあやつろうなんて
君は日本人だろう？
You're Japanese, aren't you?
なぜ黒の騎士団ではなくルルーシュ様に
Why come to Master Lelouch
instead of the Black Knights?
騎士道に殉じるか 君も
You devote yourself to
chivalry as well, don't you?
そうかもしれませんね
Perhaps you're right.
ルルーシュの部屋にC.C.がはいってきました
よく仮面をかぶりつづけたな
I'm impressed you maintained your mask,
even in front of Nunnally.
ナナリーの前で
いくつルートを探っても　答えは同じだったからな
No matter what angle I attack the problem from,
the answer is always the same.
あのときの結論にまちがいはないと
That the conclusion
I made then wasn't wrong.
ルルーシュもう十分じゃないのか？
Lelouch, haven't you done enough?
おまえはよくやった
You've done well.
ルルーシュの隣にすわるC.C.
おれが悪をなさねばならない理由はよくわかっているだろう？
You understand why
I'm doing this evil, don't you?
それに ダモクレスによる支配は
Besides, under the rule of Damocles,
people will become lifeless symbols.
人を記号とするものだ
しかし ダモクレスにはナナリーがいる
But Nunnally is aboard Damocles.
おまえは今までナナリーのために
All you've done
has been for her sake.
もう　特別扱いはできない
I can't treat her differently anymore.
消えていったあまたの命のためにも
We can't stop now,
for the sake of all those who have died.
おれたちは止まるわけにはいかないんだ
そうだろう？C.C.
Right, C.C.?
ああ　そうだなルルーシュ
Yes. You're right, Lelouch.
そのそばでナイトメアフレームをみつめるスザクの手にはアーサー
いいの？いっしょに戦うなんて
You sure you want
to be fighting with us?
ブリタニアを敵にすることになるけど
You'll be fighting against
Britannia, you know.
いまならさ
Right now...
いまならさ 君の気持ちも少しはわかる気がする
Right now, I understand
your feelings just a little bit.
え　え～っと
Um...
どういたしまして
You're welcome.
なんだそりゃ
I beg your pardon?
黒の騎士団
神聖ブリタニア帝国は　帝都ペンドラゴンが消滅したため
With the destruction of Pendragon,
the capital of the Holy Britannian Empire,
内政機能はまひしている
their internal administration
has been paralyzed.
各エリアの軍隊は　われわれ黒の騎士団と対峙しており
With them confronting the armies of
every Area as well as the Black Knights,
へたには動けない
they can't make any false moves.
つまり　こちらと戦えるルルーシュ軍は
In short, the only force Lelouch
can send against us here...
日本を再占領した部隊のみ
is just the division he
brought to reoccupy Japan.
しかし このパワーバランスはいつくずれてもおかしくありません
However, this balance of
power can collapse at any time.
被害を最小限にとどめるには
To minimize damage,
the time to confront him is now!
決戦のタイミングは今しか
シュナイゼルがわれわれに合流した以上
Now that Schneizel has joined up with us,
our forces are evenly matched.
彼我の戦力は伯仲している
フレイヤをつかったダモクレスを認める気はないが
We don't intend to approve of
Damocles's use of F.L.E.I.J.A. weaponry,
この場は世界がまとまることを優先したい
but uniting the world has priority here.
This battle...
この戦いが
この戦いこそが世界をかけた決戦となる
その言葉をひきつぐルルーシュ
This battle is a showdown
with control of the world at stake!
シュナイゼルと黒の騎士団を倒せば
If we defeat Schneizel and the Black Knights,
then there will be none left to stand in our way!
わが覇道をはばむものは一掃される
世界は ブリタニア皇帝唯一ルルーシュによって破壊され
The world shall be destroyed...
and then recreated by Lelouch,
the one, true emperor of Britannia!
しかるのちに創造されるだろう
打ち砕くのだ！敵を！シュナイゼルを！
Smash them! Smash Schneizel!
Smash the enemy!
天空要塞ダモクレスを！
Smash the sky fortress Damocles!
おそれることはない
We have nothing to fear!
未来は　我が名とともにあり！
My name is the future of this world!
オール　ハイル　ルルーシュ！
All hail Lelouch!
シュナイゼル
ルルーシュは　世界のすべてに悪意をふりまく存在だ
Lelouch spreads malice
over the entire world.
平和の敵はこの地で討たねばならない
As the enemy of peace,
he must be wiped out.
過去のしがらみは捨て
I want us and the Black Knights to throw off
the fetters of the past and join forces here!
私たちも　黒の騎士団も
ここはともに手をたずさえたい
世界中の人々が待っている
The people of the world are waiting!
For our song of victory!
私たちの凱歌を
そして願わくば
And I pray that this is the last war
that mankind need ever fight!
これが人類にとって　最後の戦争であることを祈りたい
ルルーシュ
Lelouch...
学校でとった写真をみつめるアーニャ
ふたりとも 記録にしてあげる
I'll make both of you
into recordings.
アーニャは大丈夫なのですか？
シュナイゼルたちの部屋
Are you sure
Anya will be all right?
殿下は記憶を戻すとおっしゃられましたが
I know you promised to restore
her memory, Your Highness, but...
今は少しでも戦力が必要だよだから
We need every bit of
battle strength we have. So...
そこへルルーシュから通信
ほ～うオープンチャンネルで
Oh? On an open channel, too.
ごきげんようシュナイゼル
You look well, Schneizel.
ルルーシュ降伏するなら今のうちだよ
Lelouch, if you're going
to surrender, now is the time.
こちらには　フレイヤの用意がある
We have F.L.E.I.J.A.s here,
ready to use.
フレイヤ？
F.L.E.I.J.A.s? I wonder if
you'd dare to fire them.
撃てるかな？あなたに
わが旗艦アヴァロンには各合衆国の代表方がおられるが
Considering I have the U.F.N.
representatives aboard the Avalon with me.
人質をたてとする気か
He's hiding behind
the hostages?!
そこまでやるなんて
I can't believe
he'd go this far!
シュナイゼル
I know they're not directly
related to you, Schneizel, however...
あなたにとっては関係のない人たちではあるが
そうだねルルーシュ
You're right, Lelouch. They're a
small price to pay for world peace.
世界の平和とわずかな命
撃つなよシュナイゼル！
Don't shoot, Schneizel!
と　わりこむシンクー（天子?命）
各合衆国では代表代行が選出されたとききましたが
I heard the U.F.N. members have
elected substitute representatives.
いざというときの覚悟はある
We're ready for the worst.
しかしだからといって無駄にしていい命など存在しない！
But that doesn't mean their
lives are to be thrown away!
ははははっ
リ　シンクー
わが方の戦力は　このダモクレス以外は
Li Xing-ke, the only power we have aside
from Damocles is a single Mordred.
モルドレッド一機のみ
フレイヤをつかわないのであれば
If we're not to use the F.L.E.I.J.A.s, I'd like
to take command of all our forces, please.
この場は全体の指揮権を私に預けてほしいが
相手はルルーシュだ
We're facing Lelouch!
心配はいらないよ
Have no fear. I've never lost to Lelouch even once.
私はね
一度だってルルーシュに負けたことはないんだ
わかった
Understood.
シェンフーをだす
Deploy the Shen Hu. Transmit the
command structure to all forces!
全軍に指揮系統を伝達してくれ
はい
まずは手合わせといきましょうか
Yes, sir!
Then shall we have at each other?
そうだね
Indeed.
通信を切ります
カノン君のよみどおりに
Kannon, just as you predicted.
はいこれで黒の騎士団は　殿下の手足です
Yes. Now the Black Knights are yours to command.
ふっ全軍にパターンシグマを伝えて
Transmit pattern Sigma to all forces.
敵軍　航空部隊を広範囲に展開させようとしています
Enemy forces deploying into
a wide-field aerial formation.
通常戦闘でくるか
He's coming at me with
conventional tactics? Good.
よし
左翼をのばせ半月羅漢の陣を敷く
Stretch our left wing!
Assume Half-Moon Arhat formation!
イエス　ユア　マジェスティ！
Yes, Your Majesty!
敵本陣が手薄ですが
The enemy's main unit
is undermanned.
ジノの部隊は前進
Have Gino's unit advance.
敵左翼がのびる先をおさえて
Keep the enemy's left wing
from extending!
イエス　ユア　ハイネス
Yes, Your Highness!
牽制か　こちらの左翼を後退させろ
Checking my move, huh?
Move our left wing back!
それでは陣形がくずれます
That will break our formation!
よい
Very well!
ジノ進撃を停止
Gino, halt your advance!
なぜです？陣形の崩れた今こそ
Why? We should strike now
while their formation is breaking.
誘いの隙だよ
He's baiting us with an opening.
I'm not taking it.
のることはない
つられないか
Not falling for it, huh?
陣立てを北斗七星陣に変更
Switch main battle plan
to Big Dipper formation!
６番隊はアーニャを中心に北東へ
Unit 6, follow Anya and move to the
northeast, elevation 40 degrees!
仰角40度
砲撃部隊　対空戦闘準備
Bombardment unit,
prep for anti-air combat!
アーニャそこで停止２００ｍ上昇
Anya, stop there
and climb 200 meters!
なんだよ！全然戦いにならねえ！
What the hell!
Nobody's fighting at all!
違う達人同士の戦いが一瞬で決まるように
You're wrong. A battle between
two masters is decided in an instant.
みえない攻撃が2人の間を行きかっている
An invisible battle is now raging
between the two of them.
急がないと
We have to hurry.
The battle's already begun.
もう戦闘ははじまっているのに
囲まれつつあります！
They're surrounding us!
ちっ反撃だ！
スザクのランスロットを全面に押し立てろ
Counterattack! Reinforce the
front line with Suzaku's Lancelot!
第４速度でいい
Hold at combat speed 4!
Send Ward's unit out as well!
ウォード隊も続け！
かわらないねルルーシュ
You haven't changed, Lelouch.
君は防御よりも攻撃が好きだった
You like to attack
more than defend.
だからこそのわずかな隙
Which leaves me a small
window of opportunity. Xing-ke?
シンクー？
シンクー突撃
われらの技量までおり込み済みか
Heh... He's already incorporated
our skills into his tactics, has he?
敵左翼　前進してきます
Enemy left wing, advancing!
ひるむな!陛下のご期待にこたえるのだ！
Give no quarter! Live up to His
Majesty's confidence in us!
ルルーシュを倒せば すべておわれる！
If we can defeat Lelouch, this all will end!
ここを破って　混戦にもちこめば！
If we break the line here and
turn this into a free-for-all!
うっ突破される
They're breaking through!
ひきちぎられるか
We're being cut up...
スザクくんをもどしますか？！
Shall I recall Suzaku?
いいや それがシュナイゼルの狙いだ
No, that's what Schneizel wants us to do.
戦線をさげよ陣形をたてなおす
Withdraw the battle line!
Regroup our forces!
敵艦隊　後退していきます
Enemy fleet falling back.
この機をのがすな！追撃！
Don't lose this chance! Press the attack!
紅蓮は先行しすぎだ
Guren, you're too far out! Match pace
with us and we'll surround them!
足並みをそろえて包囲しろ！
わかっています！でも
I know, but!
あせるな！
前衛部隊を砕けばアヴァロンは孤立する
Don't be in a rush! If we defeat their
vanguard, the Avalon will be left isolated!
ドレッドノート撃沈！突破されます！
Dreadnought, destroyed! They're breaking through!
黒の騎士団
So, the Black Knights are this
strong an enemy, are they?
敵にまわすとこれほどやっかいな相手だったか
しかし　我が軍の兵は　?
However, as for my own troops...
皇帝陛下のために～！
For His Majesty!
哀れだなギアスによって操られている兵士とは
It's heartbreaking. Seeing soldiers
controlled by Geass. Therefore!
ゆえに！
今かな両翼をくだこう
I suppose now is the time.
Smash both wings.
艦首拡散ハドロン重砲セット！
Bow-mounted hadron
scatter cannon, set!
7番隊　射角外へ移動！
Move squad 7 out of the firing angle!
ゲフィオンコントロール　同調よし
Gefjun control, synched.
いけます
敵軍両翼にむけ　発射！
Ready to fire!
Target both enemy wings.
Fire!
ゼロみんなの力をあわせれば
Zero, with everyone joined together,
we can defeat you!
君を倒せる！
ルルーシュは黒の騎士団を過小評価していたようですね
It seems Lelouch underestimated
the Black Knights.
ルルーシュ！
とディートハルト
ああさすがだな
Lelouch!
Right. I'm impressed.
You've forced me to use this plan, now.
この策を使わせるとは
しまった！
エネルギー反応 下からです
Dammit!
Energy reaction, right below us!
何っ？
まさかこのタイミングで
What?! Impossible...
He timed this to?!
全軍　輻射障壁を展開しろ！
All forces!
Raise radiant shields!
ゼロ！
Zero!
最初にゼロ ルルーシュを認めてしまったのは俺だ
I was the one who first recognized
Zero's... Lelouch's leadership.
だから俺には責任がある
That's why this is my responsibility.
しかし 新しい命は巻き込みたくない
But I don't want
a new life caught up in this.
勝手なお願いなのはわかっている
I know this is a selfish
request I'm making,
でも 君にはこの蓬莱島に残ってほしい
but I want you stay
here on Horai Island.
扇さん！応答してください！
Ohgi, please respond!
Minami! Rakshata!
南さん！ラクシャータさん！
そ そんな
It... It can't be!
しかし　サクラダイトをつかって
He used the sakuradite
in the mine?
これでは　ルルーシュの地上部隊も全滅だね
This has destroyed Lelouch's
ground forces as well.
うかつ！
I was careless!
ルルーシュの基本戦術ではあったが
That's Lelouch's basic tactic.
味方を犠牲にすることが前提とは
But how can he sacrifice
his own forces?!
これで　敵の戦力は絞られた
This has left the enemy's strength nearly
depleted. That leaves Damocles...
後はダモクレスを
たたくだけ！
For us to hit!
残念だが チェックをかけられたのは君たちの方だよ
Unfortunately, it's you who
have been checked here.
ナナリー 照準は合わせてある
Nunnally, targeting is complete.
黒の騎士団がついえた今
Now that the Black Knights have been
smashed, we must use F.L.E.I.J.A.'s power.
フレイヤという力で
は はい
Y-Yes...
お兄様の罪は　私が討ちます
With this act, I will wipe away
big brother's sins!
きました！フレイヤです！！
Incoming! It's a F.L.E.I.J.A.!
ここで撃ってきたか第三特装師団
So, here's where he's fired it.
Special equipment division 3!
イエス　ユア　マジェスティ
Yes, Your Majesty!
無駄だよ
このフレイヤは　ダモクレスから射出されたときには臨界状態にある
It's useless. The F.L.E.I.J.A. went critical
the moment it was fired from Damocles.
アヴァロンはこのまま後退
Avalon will continue to fall back.
All forces, charge at Damocles.
各部隊はダモクレスにに突撃しフレイヤを撃たせ続けろ
Make them keep firing F.L.E.I.J.A. s
until they exhaust their stock!
弾切れにおいこむんだ
扇さんによびかける玉城とカレン
扇！扇！
Ohgi! Ohgi!
扇さん！
Ohgi!
死んだふりしてる場合か！
Is this any time
to be playing dead?!
ま まさか おまえたち　盾になって
I... I don't believe it.
You two shielded us?
へへっブリッジぐらいしか守れなかったけどよ
We were only able to
protect the bridge, though.
まあとは自力でなんとかしてくれ
You're on your own now.
行くぞ！カレン！
Let's go, Kallen!
何よえらそうに
Oh please, look who's
giving orders now.
ちっ富士の作戦を使ってしまった以上
Now that I've used the Fuji plan,
I calculate his remaining F.L.E.I.J.A.s...
フレイヤの残弾から計算すると
こちらが一手不利になる
put me at a one-move
disadvantage.
とすると ニーナを頼りにするしかないが
Meaning I have to
depend on Nina now.
あてにできるか？
Can she do it?
I know she hates me.
俺を憎んでいるはずだ
ユフィのかたき　ゼロであった俺を
Hates me for being Zero,
Euphy's murderer.
しかし シュナイゼルを倒すためには
But, to defeat Schneizel...
ルルーシュ もし私を倒そうと考えているのなら
Lelouch, if you're thinking
that you can defeat me,
君はそこまでだよ
you've reached
the end of the line.
仮面を使いこなせない人間に　勝利はない
For a man who has not mastered
the use of a mask can never prevail.
Dakuse wa oni
This corrupt world is filled with demons
Seigi wa nanzo to
What is justice?
Tou mae ni aragae yo
Resist, don't just question
Akutoku no hana
The flower of evil
Gizen no yume
Dreams of hypocrisy
Mishi me niwa me wo sashi
Give your gaze to the eyes that see them
Sei mo ja mo wakatareru koto nashi
The line between right and wrong cannot be known
Hikari wa tae taiji no you ni
Light is gone, and you slumber
Kimi wa nemuru yami no shikyuu
Like an unborn child in the womb of darkness
Kodoku koso itooshii
Isolation is what you love
Yui-itsu no mikata to naru darou
It will probably be your only ally
Hitori hitori chishio ni mamire
One by one, stained with the tide of blood
Kono jidai ni umare ochita
You were born into this era
Erabareshi oujira yo
Oh, chosen princes
Tatakai koso shukuen
Battle shall be your banquet
Aa ware wa uruwashii zenchi
Oh, I am graceful omniscience
Ai no haha
The loving mother
Kimi wo umu
Who bore you
Kono chichi ni hagukumishi mono wa
The ones who were raised on my breast
Jigoku no harakara
Are your brethren in hell
Mokushi no in
The mark of apocalypse
Shinri wa nanzo to
What is truth
Shirimosezu uzumoreshi intoku no tane
A seed of secrecy buried where no one knows
Moroha no ken
A double-edged sword
Nuku ha niwa ha wo muke
Turn its blade upon the unsheathed blade
Mamorubeki mono dake wo shinjite
Believe only in what you must protect
Aru ga mama ni kimi wa
And in your own way
Kimi wo hanate
You'll set yourself free
オレとスザク二人が手を組めば出来ないことは無い
Suzaku and me. Together,
there's nothing we can't accomplish.
そのはずだった
しかしフレイヤが支配する戦場にもはや戦術は通用しないのか？
That's what I thought,
but now...
The fearsomeness of Schneizel.
The truth is, it's his
lack of personal desires.
最後の鍵は？そのカードは？
What sort of strategy will come from
a man who knows about Geass,
possesses F.L.E.I.J.A.,
and is determined to achieve his goal?
ルルーシュだ
今週も楽しんでくれてありがとう
Can no tactic work now on a
battlefield dominated by F.L.E.I.J.A.?
いつも応援してくれているみんなにご覧のプレゼントを送る
There's one last gamble to try,
one final card to play.
こちらのケータイサイトから応募してほしい
And it lies within
Schneizel's own heart.
本日中の受付だ
THE GRIP OF DAMOCLES
もちろん　特製待受けもあるぞ
それでは諸君　来週もお楽しみに